Shalu Shalu

Professional Summary

UI designer with a professional background as an Assistant and Web designer experienced in web and mobile applications including product design within various industries. Passionate in designing products and applications according to the user's needs and experience and making human-centred designs aesthetical and simple.

Work Experience (4 years)

Victorious infotech pvt ltd - Freelance UI/UX Designer

Toronto, ON

11/2022 - Current

- Researching and analyzing the user problem and working on the online learning education website.
- Collaborating with the product manager and evaluating their project requirements.
- Responsible for the whole design system, prototyping and high-fidelity mockups.

Academy projects - UX/UI Designer

Toronto, ON

11/2021 - 07/2022

Financial group

Fintech app that helps people to manage their budgets. The user could get cash back on daily shopping and track their fund transactions of regular expenses.

- Researched user problems and analyzed their pain points, and competitive analysis, and created user stories.
- Understanding user pain points, created user-centric design solution and prepared a User flow diagram.
- Created low-fidelity wireframes with user-centric solutions on papers and prepared digitized wireframes with UI design principles and had given them for user testing.
- After user feedback applied the iterations and created high-fidelity wireframes and prepared a responsive design and mockup.

Tools: Figma, photoshop, creative cloud

<u>Yummy Tummy</u>

- ✓ shaluoad97@gmail.com
- 416 821 4390
- O Toronto, Canada M3C 1S6

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://www.behance.net/Shaluoad_90
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/shalu0907
- https://shaluportfoliowebsite.github.io/ Shaluportfoliowebsite/index.html

Skills

- User research, user persona
- Information Architecture, Sitemap
- Design UI design patterns
- Building UI design system, components
- User research, competitive analysis
- Product design, User flow diagram, Wireframes
- Building Cohesive brand
- Style guide, Responsive designs
- Prototyping (Marvel, Invision)
- Usability and A/B testing and iteration
- Final designs, Mockups
- User Interface Design
- UI animation
- Html, Css and Java script

Tools

Figma

Recipe web application for everyone! It gives access to online grocery shopping at home easily. Provides simple, delicious, customizable recipes with built-in shopping list for your convenience.

- Researched user requirements worked on UX Lean and worked at UCD (User Centered designs), Human-Computer Interaction.
- Conducted user's interviews, worked on User personas and analyzed User problems and found solutions.
- Created user flow diagram and wireframe from low to high fidelity.
 Created style guide and applied User Interfaces.
- Usability testing(Rapid prototyping testing) and iterations
- Created final designs and mockups

Tools: Sketch, Marvel

Jarviz Infosec Pvt Ltd - Assistant Designer

Gurugram, India

12/2014 - 08/2017

MobileSOS

A women's safety application with unique functions such as "Shake your Device" without getting noticed in an emergency to contact near and dear ones.

- Created wireframes from low to high fidelity according to the product requirement, applied visual design and created prototypes.
- Engineered prototypes to support research and usability testing.
 Collaborated with teammates to deliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs.

Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

MobileHeal Pro

Offers advanced safety and security to Android smartphones and services like managing your data from mobile to desktop, finding your phone, and data recovery.

- Created icons and UI elements for the User Interface including a style guide and applied it to the responsive designs.
- Collaborated with developers and the Ux team and worked on rapid prototyping and usability tests.

Tools: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD

Antheia infrastructure pvt ltd - Web Designer

Gurugram, , India

07/2014 - 11/2014

www.propchill.com

It was a real estate website development project where users could buy/sell/rent properties.

- Worked on front-end development using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and Bootstrap.
- Collaborated with the team, Identified and eliminated website bugs to improve user experience

Sketch

Photoshop

Illustrator

Prototype (Invision, Marvel)

Wireframe(Balsamiq)

Atom

GitHub

Flinto

Education

08/2022

Careerfoundry

Toronto, ON

Certificate in UI Designer

Specialization in Mobile and Web

application

06/2014

Rajasthan Technical University

Kota, India

Master of Science: Master in Computer

Application

08/2011

Bachelor in Computer Application

India

Bachelor of Science: Computer Applications Development